Here are your refreshments.
Oh, thank you.
Here you go, Nami-san.
Thank you.
Let me know anytime you want a refill.
Hey, Usopp!
Usopp!
What? Don't bother me now...
Chopper!
What in the world are they doing?
I like how it's cheerful.
Monkey D. Luffy, a boy who aspires to
become the King of the Pirates, and his crew,
Zoro, Nami, Usopp, Sanji, and Chopper,
added Nico Robin to the group
at a desert kingdom Alabasta
and were continuing their journey
on the Grand Line.
Navigator-san, by the way...
Are you checking logs?
Straight to west-northwest!
No problem! We're on our way!
Okay. If I remember right,
the island next to Alabasta is Autumn Island.
Rain?
What?
Ouch.
It's not rain...
It's...
A galleon?!
How?!
What is it? What?! Hey! What?!
More stuff's falling! Watch out!
Wow! Cool! What's happening?!
Luffy, protect the ship!
It can't take this!
Okay! Count on...
What's this?
Hey, Nami! I got something!
This is no time for that!
Why the heck did a ship fall from the sky?
How weird!
There's nothing in the sky...
What's wrong, Nami-san?
Our Log Pose is...
...broken!
It's stuck pointing upwards!
What should we do?
We can't get to the next island without it!
--That's not it.
--What?
It was updated by an island
with stronger magnetism.
What?!
If the Log Pose needle is pointing upwards,
that means the log has been caught
by a Sky Island.
Sky Island?!
Oh yeah. Earlier, I found...
What's that?
Skypiea? A map of a Sky Island?!
What?!
No way... Does this mean that
there's really an island in the sky?!
Let's go, Nami! It's a dream island!
We can go to a dream island!
Yay! Awesome!
Skypiea! Skypiea! Come on!
--Skypiea!
--How are we gonna get there?
What?
This map doesn't show how to get there!
Even if there's a Sky Island,
we don't know the way to get there!
You're the navigator!
Figure something out!
There are some things you can't
just "figure out," you know!
Monsters!
ONE PIECE
EPISODE OF SKY ISLAND
JAYA
It's good that we arrived at this island
called Jaya,
but if the Log Pose stays like this,
we have no choice but to go to the Sky Island.
Well, it'll be alright.
Alright.
Nami-san! Just for ladies,
I made never-before-eaten takoyaki!
Well, I wasn't counting on you guys
from the start.
I got information.
The town drawn on the left is
Mock Town, where we are now.
And you see an X on the other side, right?
I heard a man who doesn't
blend in on Jaya lives there.
Doesn't blend in?
EASTERN COAST, JAYA
--A...
--Amazing!
Idiots! Look closely.
What the...?! It's just a board?!
What?!
Hello?
I'm coming in!
No one's home...
Hello!
NOLAND THE LIAR
A picture book...
This is quite an old book.
It's titled "Noland The Liar."
Wow, that's a cool title!
"This is a story from long, long ago...
A story that took place 400 long years ago.
A man named Mont Blanc Noland
lived in a North Blue country.
Noland, an explorer, always talked about
his incredible adventures.
However, the villagers couldn't tell
if those stories were true or not.
One day, he reported to the king
after coming back from his travels.
'I saw a mountain of gold on
an island in the great sea.'
The courageous king set sail to the great sea
to see if the story was true.
After surviving great adventures,
the king and Noland made it to the island.
However, what they found there
was just a jungle.
In the end, he was sentenced to death
for the crime of lying.
Noland's last words were as follows:
'That's right!
The mountain of gold sank in the sea!'
The king and the others were dumbfounded.
No one believed Noland any longer
because Noland continued to
lie until his very death.
The end"
Liars always end up miserable.
Don't keep looking at me!
"Noland The Liar," huh? That takes me back.
I often read it when I was a kid.
You know it, Sanji-kun? But it says
it was published in the North Blue.
Yeah. I was born in the North Blue.
This is a famous story in the North.
There's a weird bird.
You're right.
What are you doing?!
MONT BLANC CRICKET - LAST BOSS OF
PIRATE GROUP "MONKEY MOUNTAIN ALLIED FORCE"
Who the hell are you?!
You're after the gold, aren't you? Die!
What?
Hey, Usopp! Go grab Luffy!
G-Got it!
--Sanji!
--Sanji-kun!
Don't worry. It didn't hit me.
The bends?
Yeah, it's a sickness that
divers sometimes get.
Sorry I caused you trouble.
I thought you were just more idiots
after gold bullion.
--Gold bullion?!
--Pops, don't get up!
Thank you, Doctor. You're quite skilled.
Your compliment doesn't
make me happy, you fool!
What is it that you wanna ask me?
Pops! Are those giant monkeys your pets?
Is that what you had to ask?!
They're Masira and Shoujou.
They're my underlings.
I've been diving into the sea
to search for gold every day.
Nice!
Then, one day, they suddenly came
saying they wanted to help search for gold.
Well, putting the monkey story aside...
Why even ask?!
I wanna go to the Sky Island!
Please tell us how to get there!
You believe in the Sky Island?
What?! There's no Sky Island?
No one knows...
I know someone who said there is.
But people call him a legendary big liar,
Mont Blanc Noland.
There's a picture book about him
called "Noland The Liar."
What?
I'm Mont Blanc Cricket.
Noland's my granddad's
granddad's granddad's...
He's my distant ancestor.
The Montblanc Family was
driven out of the country then,
and has kept a low profile,
people continue to denounce our family to this day.
But no one in the family hates him.
Why?
Because Noland was an
extraordinarily honest person.
Noland's last excuse in the
picture book is like this.
"That's right! The mountain of gold
sank in the sea!"
A stupid-looking face is drawn in this book,
but he shed many tears and
died a regrettable death.
Noland insisted that the ruins had submerged
due to crustal movements,
but everyone thought he was making
excuses out of desperation.
In front of the laughing onlookers,
Noland was executed.
Oh, I see! You're looking for the city of gold
on the seabed...
...in order to clear the
Montblanc Family's name!
No...
If it's there, that's fine.
If it's not there, that's fine, too.
It's not that I want to prove his innocence.
This is a duel with the man, Noland,
who threw a wrench into my life.
I wanna go to the Sky Island, Pops!
Yeah, I did tell you, right?
The witness to the Sky Island
is that Noland the Liar.
What?! A logbook?!
Could it be Noland's?
He mentions the Sky Island in it.
What?!
Let's see...
Hurry up!
Don't rush me!
I heard there is a vehicle called a Waver
on the Sky Island.
Oh, yeah! A Waver!
What? Let me see!
It also says he saw Sky Fish.
Sky Fish?!
Sky Fish, huh?
That's something to look forward to.
--It's such a valuable logbook.
--Look over here!
"The sound of the bell that's made of giant gold
resonated far and wide."
So there's a gold bell!
And here!
"I saw gold in the skull's right eye."
You're so quick at finding
where it mentions gold.
There's a strange phenomenon
that occurs in these waters a few times a month.
It'll turn to night,
even though it's the middle of the day.
There are clouds known as
"Imperiocumulus Clouds."
When those giant clouds
appear high in the sky,
even sunlight is blocked out,
bringing afternoon "nighttime" to the ground.
Listen. If a Sky Island really does exist,
that'd be the only possible place!
What do you mean?
Go above the Imperiocumulus Clouds
by getting on the Monstrous Current!
A current that shoots up into the air.
That is called a Monstrous Current.
The accepted theory goes like this.
Deep beneath the sea floor,
there are large cavities,
and low-temperature
sea water seeps into them.
The heat from the earth below
turns that water into steam,
and the resulting pressure causes
a huge explosion on the sea floor.
It occurs five times a month.
But if the Sky Island doesn't show up
above the current when we rise up,
we'll all slam into the sea surface
and end up at the bottom of the sea.
We reinforced your ship.
Masira and Shoujou did their job.
Strength, speed, weight...
All the adjustments are done.
Go for it!
Let's go to the Sky Island!
How exciting! I thought we got blown away!
The ship's going straight up a pillar of water!
How is this happening?!
We're not gonna fall?!
Alright! Go, Merry!
Now we can go into the sky at once!
It was falling...
Yeah, it was...
Definitely falling...
What should we do?!
Is that what'll happen to us?!
We'll die! We'll slam into the sea and die!
Spread the sails! Right away!
What?
This is the sea! Not just a pillar of water!
It's a rising current!
And the wind blowing from below
is a rising air current
produced by the geothermal heat
and steam explosion!
If we're dealing with wind and sea,
I can navigate it!
Who's this ship's navigator?!
You are, Nami-san!
We're gonna fall! We're gonna fall, Nami!
Do something!
No, we can make it!
Awesome! The ship is flying!
Is this for real?!
Nami-san! You're wonderful!
We did it!
Kid! There's one thing
that's a definite fact.
No one in history's ever disproved
the City of Gold or the Sky Island.
Right!
People might laugh and call it
foolish logic, but it's enough for me.
That's what romanticism is all about!
What's that?
A wall of clouds?!
We can't slow down...
We'll plunge into it like this!
Can't... Can't breathe...!
What's happening?!
An ocean in the sky?
Clouds?!
We're in the clouds?!
How are we staying on them?!
Of course you can stay on them!
They're clouds!
No, you can't!
You sure?!
KAMI'S TEMPLE, UPPER YARD
For six years...
KAMI
I've been living in this Kami's Temple
and finally...
the Maxim is complete.
THE SKY ISLAND'S ONE AND ONLY KAMI ENERU
I wish I could say that,
but it is almost finished.
Oh, then...
Must be hard to talk while
you're biting your lower lip!
How careless of me.
So let's put an end to this island
and set forth...
...for the world of dreams!
What's the matter?
A group of seven...
They're trying to invade my country.
Only the almighty Kami Eneru could tell that!
He's out of our league!
Somebody, give unto them Heaven's Judgment!
I am the Kami.
Wh-What the...?!
What?! What's going on?! A lobster?!
Where is he gonna take us?!
Ask the lobster!
What is this?! A river of clouds?!
I don't think it's naturally occurring.
It's definitely unnatural!
Something's written there!
"Godland..."
"Skypiea"?
An island!
It's a Sky Island!
Are you Blue Sea people?
What's that? Who are you?!
I am the Sky Knight.
"Blue Sea people" is the term for
those who live beneath the clouds.
In other words, did you come up here
from the Blue Sea?
Yeah. That's right.
Old guy, what are you drinking?
This? Pumpkin juice. It's my favorite.
That sounds delicious.
Hey! There are so many other important things
that we have to ask!
Is that Sky Fish?!
--I wonder if it tastes good!
--Hey!
Pierre!
"SKY KNIGHT" GANFOR
I am the Sky Knight!
Ganfor!
--Yay!
--Old guy, you're strong!
Oh, no!
Mouton Mallet!
Dragon Twister!
Gum-Gum...
...Gatling!
CONIS - A RESIDENT OF SKYPIEA
SUU - A CLOUD FOX
My name is Conis. This is Suu, a Cloud Fox.
Thank you for saving me from danger.
Heso!
H-Heso?
Hey, what is this vehicle?
Oh, it's a Waver.
So this is a Waver!
How does it work?
There's no sail to catch the wind...
How did you propel it on the sea?
Oh, you mean you're not familiar with Dials?
Dials?
Seashells like this.
This is a little small but it's a Wind Dial.
The Waver moves by blowing wind
that was stored in this Wind Dial.
--Oh...
--That's amazing!
Guys!
Hey, she's riding it!
How awesome! This is like a dream!
Ya-hoo!
Yeah! It's so cool!
Gee! I can ride it, too!
Hey!
What is he doing?
Seems like he's a power-user
but this sea has no bottom.
What?!
Jeez! He almost dropped through the bottom!
I felt... my foot... coming
out of... the cloud...
Heso! I found you, criminals!
Criminals?!
Did we do something?
Who are you?
My name is Satori!
SATORI OF THE FOREST
KAMI'S VASSAL OF SKYPIEA
You guys entered this
country without permission.
I'm going to punish you
in the name of Kami Eneru!
The almighty Kami Eneru
watches over everything.
You guys will be sacrifices to Kami!
Cut the crap!
You wanna fight, right? You got it!
Criminals must be punished!
Die!
Surprise Ball Attack! Ball Dragon!
I should just beat you, right?
Oh, you're going to stretch?
Gum-Gum... What?
...Pistol!
Damn you!
Oh, I see!
An upper kick with the right foot...
Collier... What?!
Sanji!
Luffy!
--Those two got beaten so easily!
--Kami's vassals use Mantra!
Mantra?
What's with him?!
He predicted my movements!
And regular hits have no effect on Luffy!
It's not a regular hit!
That's the Impact Dial.
It's different from a hit.
It's an impact!
That's right! The shock destroys
the body from the inside!
Damn!
What the...?!
Chopper!
Suu!
Nami!
They got kidnapped?!
That's the Lobster Express!
If you don't stop it soon,
they'll be taken to Upper Yard!
Upper Yard?
That's Kami's island!
It's where the Sacrificial Altar is!
Kami?
Let me borrow this!
Navigator-san isn't enough.
Is there any other boat?
Yes! Over there!
Zoro!
Look after Nami and the others!
I'll catch up with you
after I beat this jerk!
Got it.
UPPER YARD - THE ISLAND WHERE KAMI LIVES
Oh, no! It seems like
Shura is headed for the Sacrificial Altar!
Huh? Who's Shura?
He's Kami's vassal! He can fly like me!
He's "Sky Rider" Shura!
This is...
"SKY RIDER" SHURA - KAMI'S VASSAL OF SKYPIEA
FUZA - A RIDING ROC
...the Sacrificial Altar.
And you guys are...
...the sacrifices.
Just give up...
No!
--Just give up...
--No!
Oh, how annoying!
All you do is run?!
Whoa! It burns?!
No! Don't burn the Merry!
In order to more deeply
realize your own fault,
offer your life to Kami!
No!
Suu!
Die!
No!
Sorry to have kept you waiting!
Sky Knight!
Hmph! It's the old previous Kami!
He is quite good.
He is a worthy opponent.
Let's get rough with him, Pierre.
Ganfor!
You dare to step into Upper Yard
and get in the way of my judgment!
Sky... Knight...!
And you dare to rebel against Kami Eneru!
There's no telling what will come out!
That's my "Ball Challenge"!
Surprise Cloud Strike! Go!
Oh, no! Go away!
Huh?
A dud...
What?! You scared me! This crap...
Did it scare you?
Now, a bunch of gunpowder balls...
Ball Dragon!
Here we go!
Luffy! Dodge!
Damn!
--Luffy!
--Why are you running the same way?!
Oh, yeah!
What?!
Oh, I see!
It was controlled by this string.
I'll take care of this thing!
What impudence!
Just hang on and come to me!
What?!
Don't hang on with the other hand, too!
That was close! What an unbelievable idiot!
You're right. That was close.
Yeah, it was... No!
You're still alive?!
Get off of me! You idiot! Idiot!
Don't let him go, Luffy!
Don't ever let go of that doughboy!
Oh, Sanji! You're alive?!
I almost died because of you!
Pay more attention to others!
I'm alive, too...
Well, in any case,
helpless ladies are
waiting for me to come to their rescue.
Let's finish this up!
Doughboy!
Stop it! Stop it!
It hu...
Concasser Crush!
It hurts!
HIDDEN CLOUD VILLAGE
STATUE OF GREAT WARRIOR KALGARA
Your Mantra is saying so, Aisa?
Yeah.
You can't hear one voice anymore.
Yes, I think it's Satori, Kami's Vassal.
And Shura is the one who got hurt.
WARRIOR WYPER - A SHANDIAN
I see!
Now is our chance!
Upper Yard is rattled right now!
This is the opportunity of a lifetime!
Don't fear Kami!
We vow to the Great Warrior Kalgara
to bring back the Light of Shandora!
Yeah!
Wyper! Don't we have to take care of them?
Not now! It's more important that...
...we don't miss this chance!
They're gone...
Looks like we're not their targets.
Who are they?
They're... the Shandians!
They're guerrillas who rebel against Kami Eneru
and his Vassals.
"SKY BREEDER" OHM
KAMI'S VASSAL OF SKYPIEA
"SKY BOSS" GEDATSU
That was close!
I almost got involved.
Don't tell me... this island is...
Sky Knight!
What did you do?! I can't move!
Is something wrong, Ganfor?!
This is my String Challenge!
Don't assume you can match me in mid-air!
If you want a shoulder, you can have one.
An Impact, huh?! Such things can't defeat me!
No, it's ten times the energy.
Reject!
The long-standing battle between
the Shandians and the people
who live on the Sky Island...
It began 400 years ago...
...when the Great Warrior Kalgara
who was protecting Shandora, the City of Gold...
...met a man.
400 YEARS AGO
Kalgara was a brave warrior
who single-handedly sank many pirate ships...
...to protect his people.
GREAT WARRIOR KALGARA
That year, they had a bad crop
and the Shandians became sick one after another.
They feared it as the work of an evil spirit,
and decided to offer Kashigami,
a giant snake believed to be
the village's protective god,
a young girl as a sacrifice.
At the same time, a visitor
arrived on the island.
MONT BLANC NOLAND
ADMIRAL OF AN EXPEDITION SHIP
FROM LVNEEL KINGDOM OF NORTH BLUE
His name was Mont Blanc Noland.
As soon as he entered a forest,
he noticed the plague that was ravaging the island.
It's the Kinetsu plague.
He hasn't been treated at all.
Doctor! Do we have any Conine left?!
Inject this lad and all of us immediately!
In exchange for this girl's life,
please save our village!
The ceremony is over.
You must've been really frightened.
You're safe now! There's no need to die!
I am an explorer from the North Blue,
Mont Blanc Noland...
It doesn't matter who you are!
Is this how you've eliminated all the few,
yet vital advancements?!
You're in no place to criticize!
Atone to the gods where you stand!
There! Use that knife to take your life!
What?!
A sacrifice meant to save the village,
crying because she wants to live...
Have you no shame?!
Don't be a fool!
Stop!
The deadly sin of Kami-killing!
You, alone, won't be enough!
You and all your men will
pay with your lives!
"Lives" this, "sacrifices" that!
Will those make your gods happy?!
These ceremonies are insults to all of us!
Give me time!
I'll banish this so-called curse of yours!
And if I can't, you can do whatever you like!
In return, if I do save
this village from tragedy,
swear to me you'll never
hold these ceremonies again!
To save the village from the crisis,
Noland went into the forest alone,
but at that time, suddenly,
an anomaly appeared on the earth.
Noland got stuck in a fissure
and couldn't get himself out.
Kalgara who believed in gods thought
that they gave him a crushing blow.
What you're doing is less than human!
You think so?
Even if the girl you saved yesterday...
...was my daughter?!
You would tell your own daughter
to end her life?!
It's you people who don't
understand how much power there is...
...in the words our Pandori
hear from the gods!
Obeying them is the way of this village!
I can't beg an exception
just because she's my child!
The Kashigami?!
It must be the Kashigami's child!
Sixty years ago, my own land
lost hundreds of thousands of lives...
...to the Kinetsu plague that
is ravaging your village now!
But, in recent years, there've been
absolutely no deaths to this disease!
Do you know why?!
Because we discovered a cure for it!
What I'm holding in my right hand
is the bark of a Cona tree!
The Conine I can extract from it is the cure!
If I return with this,
I can save the village!
Do you know how many man-hours
have been spent around the world,
and how many victims there have been?!
And you people are trampling
all over this great advancement!
That's why I say your "ceremonies"
are insults to those people!
Are you that afraid of gods?!
Answer me.
What did I just kill?!
A snake.
No!
I just broke our commandments
and killed a god!
But you call it a snake!
And you call the deadly curse
that kills our villagers a curable disease!
Will you really save my beloved village?!
Can you save it?!
I can!
Hey, Kalgara! Look at this!
What a shock! I didn't know
that snake had a grandchild...
"That snake"?
A snake, huh?
Soon, the village was saved by the cure
that Noland made.
SHANDORA, CITY OF GOLD
The City of Gold...
It's like I'm dreaming!
This bell's ringing has words to it.
Words?
So that the spirits of our ancestors
who were greeted by the heavens...
...can return to this land at
any time without getting lost,
we continue to ring this bell,
as a way to say, "We are right here."
We call this bell the "Light of Shandora."
That explains why it has
such a majestic sound!
--Do you think so?!
--Yes!
I heard this bell in a storm...
...where it shouldn't have been audible.
Noland and his people thought
they approved of each other
but one day, they were rejected by
the Shandians.
The reason was Noland and the others had,
without permission, cut down Ancestor Trees....
...that were important to the Shandians.
Botanist, my ass!
But that was a misunderstanding.
I see. those trees were
where their ancestors' spirits dwell...
We've done something
that can never be taken back...
The villagers are right to be angry.
But, Admiral!
We had no choice, given--
No excuses! I only did what satisfied me!
I'm told that aside from
proclaiming the city's existence,
that bell also served to guide
their ancestors' spirits to the island.
And we cut down...
...those trees!
What?!
Leave all the gold behind?!
Dad! Go quickly and stop them!
Don't be a fool! You know what they've done!
If we part now, we'll regret it
for the rest of our lives!
It'll probably sound like an excuse,
but for the Admiral's honor, I must say this.
Those woods of yours were already dead.
What?!
The true horror of the Kinetsu plague is...
...that it can also infect plant life.
It was because he knew this,
that the Admiral pleaded with you
without regard for his own life.
From people to forest, forest to people...
Several small islands have been
destroyed in exactly that way.
But there's nothing to worry about now.
We finished checking
the entire forest yesterday.
I'm sorry that we cut down your beloved woods
without knowing or explaining...
It'd probably still be unforgivable
even with an explanation,
but a botanist would never harm
a forest without good reason.
The Admiral doesn't hate
gods and spirits and stuff...
It's just that he always knows...
...what's most important.
I'm sorry, Noland!
Don't go yet!
At that moment, the bell rang loudly.
As though it was trying to
rebuild a precious friendship
that was almost lost to a misunderstanding.
It rang beautifully.
Noland!
Kalgara...
Come back again!
Noland...
I'll be waiting for you here!
I'll keep on ringing the bell!
So that your ship won't get lost
at sea when you return...
So that you won't lose sight
of this island during a storm...
I'll ring this bell and wait for you!
Let's meet again... my friend!!
It's okay to come back?
I will... I will come back again!!
We'll meet again! I promise you!!
Oh! There it is! The Going Merry!
Nami-san! Robin-chan! Conis-chan!
Seems like they're all okay!
Hey!
According to Noland's picture book,
when he revisited Jaya years later,
the ruins of gold were no longer there.
We know why now.
Before Luffy and the others returned,
Zoro, Robin, and I went to check.
Look over here!
Is that...
The "City of Gold" that once existed
on the ground and was seen by Noland...
...didn't sink into the ocean.
For 400 years...
This part of Jaya has been...
flying in the sky all this time!
This is the other half of the island that was ripped up.
This island was part of Jaya!
See! This is how Jaya looked 400 years ago!
Whoa! It looks like a skull!
Well?
Awesome!
Noland was referring to
the shape of the entire island.
But only half of it is left now,
so nobody could solve the mystery!
I see!
Then, the "skull's right eye" is...
Right here!
"I saw gold in the skull's right eye."
Treasure!
We did it!
Way to go, Nami-san!
It's a nice morning.
I no longer have to hear
the voices of the same old lower-world losers.
You guys, even if you're only doing it to kill your boredom,
you're too careless.
Like Satori
and Shura,
if you have a pathetic showing, I won't take you
to the Endless Varse!
Then, it's complete?
Now, let's play the game!
Everyone, look at the map.
We're here now.
The search team will go this way.
This "right eye" should have
some sort of ruins,
so watch out for enemies
and bring some gold back!
You make it sound so simple...
Alright, let's get going!
Yeah!
Chopper, you've got a lot of spunk!
I thought this forest would be
a scarier place, but it's not so bad!
Run! It's a giant snake!
How the hell can something so big
move so fast?!
Poison?!
I think we should run away...
Definitely.
Yikes!
It is said that
Upper Yard appeared in Skypiea...
...some 400 years ago.
Until then, Skypiea had been
a peaceful Sky Island.
Items from the Blue Sea that
sporadically rode up the Monstrous Current
were valuable to the Sky People.
Sky People?
That's us who live in Skypiea.
Okay.
All the earth on the Sky Islands
came into the sky in this way.
But earth the size of Upper Yard
was an unimaginable miracle.
Neither greenery nor soil is
naturally found in the sky.
We call the earth "Varse"
with a sense of admiration.
And those people who shot up into the sky
with the Varse...
...are the Shandians,
indigenous people living on Upper Yard.
So those guerrillas originally lived on
Jaya in the world below?
Yet, you guys kicked them off the island?
Yes. The Sky People stole their homeland,
due to their own greed.
The Shandians are simply trying
to take back their homeland.
Wyper!
You wanna die?!
I can't believe you used the Reject Dial!
If you use it one more time,
your body's gonna blow up!
Wyper!
I'm a descendent of the
Great Warrior Kalgara!
I'll take back the Varse and
bring back the Light of the Shandians!
The Light of the Shandians?
It's impossible...
The bell of the Shandians...
doesn't exist!
You think I didn't know?!
You've searched through Upper Yard
but you can't find the bell!
It's just a myth!
Shut up!
Today...
Eneru's head will roll!
Who is this "Kami Eneru"?
Until six years ago, I was Kami..
Did you hit your head, old man?
When I was Kami, he suddenly appeared from
some Sky Island,
and took control of Upper Yard.
My "Kami's force" was defeated by them
and is now being forced to do hard labor
somewhere.
That's already over.
Eneru!
It's been a while.
Former Kami, Ganfor!
You son of a...
I won't hurt you as long as you stay quiet.
Understood?
What are you up to?!
Give me back my subordinates!
They worked very hard for me.
Thanks to them, I have no use for this island anymore.
Oh, I decided to play a game!
What?!
It's a game in which the
survivors are winners!
The participants are 50 from my side.
20 Shandians.
From the Blue Sea people,
the four that entered the forest.
And the one here.
Me, too?!
The wounded old man can't fight
obviously.
75 people in total!
How many of them will remain after three hours?
That's the point of the game!
How many do you think?
Five!
Wait! Eneru!
--This is terrible!
--I wish Chopper were here...
I'm sorry but I've got to chase Eneru!
Hey! Are you gonna leave us ladies?!
Jeez!
Thus, on Upper Yard,
the survival game between the Straw Hats,
Eneru's Heavenly Warriors,
and the Shandians began.
One Million Volt Varie!
Whoops. Twenty voices disappeared
after that discharge.
Cloven...
...Cross!
I can go below!
This is Shandora, the City of Gold!
What was that?!
Burn...
Gum-Gum...
--...Bazooka!
I think I recognize this place...
Or not...
No, I do.
Did you laugh just now?! Huh?!
Hey! Wait!
Hey! Dammit!
Let go!
Ruins up here, too!
What's with this place?!
The ground's all crooked...
What?
What are you looking for?
The gold you're looking for
isn't here any longer.
Come to think of it, I can't find any.
It must be you who took it out from here.
Gold is a nice thing.
That glittering metal suits me well.
Then, you took the golden bell
that used to be here, too?
Golden bell?
Hey, let me down! You stupid bird!
You little...!
That took its toll...!
That bird's gonna pay!
Chopper!
Such a shame.
Do you want to get
revenge now or something?
I don't like to fight with a motive.
But...
I can feel one coming on.
The Dial Boat in the back seems worn out
so I'll go check.
Okay.
Nami-san?
No!
No! Go away!
Golden bell, huh?
What did you learn by reading the letters?
No, unfortunately, if it wasn't here
when you first came,
it didn't come to the sky after all.
No, wait... Yes! It's here.
It's here... in the sky!
When this island was
blown into the sky 400 years ago,
it's said that the chimes of a bell rang.
I see! That bell was made of gold!
Wonderful!
I've already taken aim at your heart.
Pray to Kami, swordsman from the Blue Sea!
You fool! I'll never pray to Kami!
First 36 pound...
Second 72 pound...
Third 108 pound...
Three-Sword Style!
108-Pound Phoenix!
No way...
The Iron Clouds were repelled!
No!
What is that Blue Sea person doing?!
What?!
Sango Smash!
Oh, the weird knight!
Damn!
What're you...?!
I invited your friends here!
Why have this many chunks of ruins
fallen from above?
Swordsman-san! Don't tell me you fell
all the way down here with these...
The giant snake is acting strange.
It looks like it's looking for something...
Hey, weird knight!
Pierre! Stay with me!
What happened to that bird?!
I guess when he landed,
he hit his head hard.
Is it possible... that this place is...
This is our homeland?
The bell! Where's the bell?!
It's not here.
Eneru!
Oops!
Ball Cloud!
Wait a little.
The game isn't over yet.
Game, you said?!
I started a survival game three hours ago.
My guess was that there'd be five survivors
including me.
That's exactly five people, right?
Good, he hasn't noticed I'm here.
In three minutes, it'll be three hours.
In other words, it won't do if
there're six people here right now.
Doh! He knew!
Kami's prophecy cannot fail.
Let's see, who shall disappear?
You are the one who should disappear!
A bad choice.
What an annoying snake!
El Thor!
A Devil Fruit's power?!
It's probably the Rumble-Rumble Fruit.
Among the many kinds of powers,
it's one of those said to be "invincible."
The power of lightning!
Eneru!
I've just come from Kami's Temple up above.
A tragedy... It was utterly destroyed!
Just what is your goal?!
There is a place I must return to.
Land has the place for land!
Humans have a place for humans!
And the Kami has a place for the Kami!
Each has a place to which it must return!
D-Don't tell me you...
That's right. I will drag down
every human from this sky!
Return everything to nothing!
What?!
--You're going to destroy the country!!
--That is only natural.
Don't be conceited, Eneru!
This is a world of humans!
There is no such thing as "Kami"!!
20 Million Volt...
...Varie!
Well, it's exactly the
time that I prophesied.
Now there are five!
I'm glad you've survived!
I shall bring you along with me
to the Endless Varse that I'm setting off to!
And what if we refuse?
What?
Who said we're coming with you?
We just want you to get out of our way!
Oh, boy...
Then...
...you'd better die here.
Robin!
She's a woman!
I can see that.
Until I teach your body a lesson,
you probably won't understand
our overwhelming difference in power.
Burn Bazooka!
Kari Krash!
Can't be! He erased the
bazooka's powerful fire!
You still don't get it, do you?
The energy that you can handle
is nothing to me.
30 Million Volt...
Hino Bird Zap!
Lightning Beast Kiten!
I don't believe it...! Even Zoro!
Follow me...
I'll show you something interesting.
This is the Ark Maxim.
KAMI
In this ship, we can travel
to the Endless Varse!
This can't be real...
I made it out!
Cool! Where am I?!
It looks like ruins.
So it's here? The huge golden bell?
Zoro! Hey! What're you doing?!
How could this happen...
...when you were here?!
Luffy...
Robin!
Navigator-san... was taken.
As I thought, it's apparently not
one of the five that survived...
What?
How truly irritating...
It means my prophecy was wrong.
Are you the guy? Are you Eneru?!
Luffy!
What did you do... to my crew?
Watch your mouth! I am the Kami.
I don't see anything Kami-like about you!
I don't see anything Kami-like about you!!
You'll know soon enough.
You're only a Paramethia.
You haven't got a chance!
Luffy!
El Thor!
Luffy...
It seems that you dodged it well...
60 Million Volt Lightning Dragon!
Luffy!
100 Million Volt Varie!
Is it possible that lightning
doesn't affect Luffy?
Stop it!
Because he's rubber?
It could be... that Luffy
is Eneru's one and only...
...natural enemy!
What the hell... are you?!
I'm Luffy.
I'm a pirate and a rubber man.
Rubber?
Lightning doesn't work on me!
Mantra...
Gum-Gum...
...Gatling!
Luffy!
Once I know lighting won't work,
I'll fight accordingly.
MAX 200 Million Volt Varie!
Don't tell me...
I don't have time to play
with the likes of you.
I'm Kami.
I am creating the world as I see fit.
What is that?!
It's a thundercloud.
Look! Something is floating in the sky!
Everyone! Please escape right away!
Eneru is planning on
obliterating this island!
Huh? He what?!
Don't be ridiculous!
She's telling the truth!
There is an imminent danger!
Everyone!
Leave the country!
What creepy clouds...
What on earth is he up to?
Luffy and Navigator-san
are on that ship, too?
What's that?! The thunderclouds
are turning spherical...
I'll show you something interesting.
Witness true divine power!
The sky's falling!
Kingdom Come!
Feast your eyes, rubber man,
on the falling island's despair.
No one can stop it now.
Stop it!
Luminous Forge!
Ow! Ouch!
Luffy!
Oh, no! Luffy!
Damn you! Fight me! Eneru!
He's just an idiot whose body
happens not to be affected by lightning!
I don't want...
If I have to abandon those guys
and go with you like this,
I don't want any of it anymore!!
Including your life?
Or would you rather place your hope
in the two rats that've snuck on?
What?
It seems they're serious
about rescuing you.
How utterly ridiculous.
Do you remember the name of
the Great Warrior Kalgara's close friend?
Mont Blanc Noland.
That's right. Kalgara vowed
he'd keep on ringing the bell for him.
"Bring back the Light of Shandora"?
Right. But the sound of the bell
didn't reach Noland.
Marijoa has...
...finally granted us permission
to enter the Grand Line.
As such, I wish to send you
on another mission.
Yes, it would be my pleasure!
But, I've decided my soldiers will
join you on this journey, as will I.
Understood?
Yes!
Kalgara!
Seto.
You're off to ring the bell, right?
I'll help.
Hey, Nola.
You've sure settled into these ruins!
Say! When do you suppose
Noland-san and the others will come?
That's all you ever ask when you come here.
It won't be so easy for him to come back.
He was born in the far northern seas.
He also has a family back home.
But he did promise.
As long as we keep ringing this bell here,
he'll show up sooner or later...
What's this?! This looks bad!
Come, Seto!
We have to protect the village!
Why?
Why does the island drop off here?
You fool! Did you deceive me?!
Where is all the gold you said there'd be?!
Where did the village go?!
What happened to this island?!
Kalgara! If you're alive, let me hear it!
The sound of the gold bell!
Answer me, Light of Shandora!
Noland's public execution's about to start!
Hey! This way, guys!
Six years ago,
I saw a giant city of gold on
the Grand Line island called Jaya!
The City of Gold does exist!
Then let's hear from one of your crewmen.
Is this man telling the truth?
No. It's an absolute lie.
What?! Noland-san is a liar?!
Then were all his stories fake?!
What a horrific man! He lied to the
whole kingdom and acted like a hero!
Who's that witness?!
He's not part of our crew!
Did you see Kalgara and the others?!
Admiral! What happened?!
Seize them!
Dammit!
M-Men...
For his heinous lies, Mont Blanc Noland
the Explorer is hereby sentenced...
...to death by beheading!
Liar!
He's a liar!
The Admiral'd never lie!
Admiral!
Liar! Liar! Liar! Liar!...
At that time, the bell rang.
It truly sounded like a singing voice
in praise of that miraculous land.
Kami-sama! It's a giant Varse!
Yes. Did you hear that? The singing voice
of this beautiful Varse...
It is truly the birth of holy land.
That is where...
...I must live!
What happened?!
What is this?! I can't breathe well!
--Is everyone all right?!
--Pull yourselves together!
Tend to the wounded! Hurry!
Kalgara! Intruders!
I hereby claim this Varse as mine!
I am Kami!
That's no Kami!!
Stop them, warriors!
We cannot let him take this land!!
We made a promise, didn't we, Noland...
We said we'd meet again someday.
Kalgara... Where are you now?
When you return to Jaya, what will you think
when you see we're gone?
Just wait a little longer! I'm going to tell you!
That we're right here!
Are you alive...?
I have so much to tell you...
Kalgara...
I'm just worried for your safety...
Let's meet again someday
no matter what, Noland!
Bring back the Light of Shandora!
Bring back... the Light of Shandora!!
Robin!
Luffy?!
What's that gold on your arm?!
Robin! The gold bell is at
the top of this vine, right?!
What?!
And Eneru's after it, right?!
That's right!
All right, then!
The bell!
The gold bell is up there?!
You're going for it, too?
If it does exist, it'd have to be there.
But Eneru's already after it.
Where are my Shooter and bazooka?
Your shoes were smashed up
so I left them below. Your bazooka, too.
What?!
When I transported you, I noticed
that you were all beat up.
Thunder Ball!
You amuse me, girl.
It worked! But...
But it won't help you
if I change the scale!
I'm busy. Begone!
You begone!
Special Attack! Exploding Star!
I... I'm sorry!
Usopp!
So it was you, huh?
--I met you on the boat...
--Glance.
Usopp!
--Nami!
--What?
--Save me.
--Screw that!
A Waver! Let's jump off on that!
Jump off?! Are you crazy?! At this height--
If we can land on the Island Clouds
in the center of the forest!
I see!
Usopp! Grab on!
Usopp!
Go.
Sanji-kun!
El...
...Thor!
So they jumped off...
But they haven't escaped me in the slightest.
Hey, Kami...
There's one thing I wanted to say...
No, but first...
Thanks...
I was just thinking...
How I wanted a light...!
And? What else?
Oh...
Drop dead...
No... you didn't!
Damn you! What were you
doing inside the ship just now?!
Damn you Blue Sea person!
Nami fell safely into some Island Clouds!
Usopp Hopping!
Long-nose-kun?!
Yes.
There they are!
Navigator-san!
What? Luffy went up?!
Yes.
Okay. I'll go after him on the Waver!
We gotta get off this island!
This ship is not so easily brought down.
Now, then. I'm above Giant Jack.
I doubt anyone would come
searching for something...
...in these skies above Kami's Temple.
Where is the golden bell...?
Brilliant!!
This is the great bell tower
the pride of the legendary city, Shandora!
Wonderful!
As the Kami, I'll take this with me
and finish my ascent to the Endless Varse!!
Luffy!
What? Nami! What're you doing here?!
It's bigger than the last one! That bastard!
Luffy! Get on, so we can go back down!
I can't.
You can't? Why not?!
Even if I don't have to save you now,
I still have unfinished business here!
Will you quit it, already?! You--
You saw it yourself!
Saw what?
The City of Gold... it existed!
What?
He's gonna ring the bell?
Yeah.
It is important that we, the inheritors
of Kalgara's wishes, ring that bell!
What does this have to do with Straw Hat?!
400 years ago, an explorer
told a lie that he saw the City of Gold.
Although people laughed at him,
his descendants believed his words
and are still searching
for this City of Gold.
That's why Luffy...
It wasn't a lie!
He wasn't lying!
So I have to let the old guy
and the others below know...
...that the City of Gold was in the sky!
Luffy...
I can't let Eneru take it!
I'm sure the huge bell can be heard
from anywhere...
...so I'm gonna ring that golden bell!
Oh! Watch out!
Some... Something's falling!
Everyone, heads down!
What?
What's that?
"Cut down this huge vine
so it falls towards the west."
Is it from Nami?!
Reject!
--We're gonna jump, Luffy!
--Okay!
Here I come! Eneru!
Gimme the Golden Bell!
They're a bunch of...
Enough of this! I'm sick of you!
Kingdom Come!
Disappear with the land!
Nami, thanks! There's no way
I'll let your help go to waste!
Huh? What?!
Gum-Gum Fireworks!
Golden Peony!
What is this abnormal electric discharge?!
That's right...! He has gold, which can
transmit electricity, on his hand!
Let the Sun shine!!
Ring it! Straw Hat!
The "Light of Shandora"!
KAMI
Here I come! I'll ring it
and you right along with it!
You insolent brat!
200 Million Volt Amaru!
Gum-Gum...
...Golden Rifle!
Reach!!
When you return to Jaya, what will you think
when you see we're gone?
Just wait a little longer! I'm going to tell you!
That we're right here!
Bring back the Light of Shandora!
I saw a giant city of gold on
the Grand Line island called Jaya!
The City of Gold does exist!
Reach!!
No one in history's ever disproved
the City of Gold or the Sky Island.
That's what romanticism is all about!
Reach!!
Sorry to have kept you waiting so long,
Mont Blanc Noland.
I hope this reaches your descendants!
Can you hear it?! Old diamond-head!
Monkeys!
The City of Gold was...
...there!!
This is romanticism.
My ancestor wasn't a liar.
You rang it to tell me that from the sky...
Right, kid?
The City of Gold was there, huh?!
I appreciate it.
The sound of the bell boasted of the glories of
the vanished city as the "Light of Shandora."
It declared the end of the fighting with a love song,
the "Song of the island"...
After being silenced for 400 years,
the golden bell fulfilled its promise.
Once its people entrusted words
to the sound of that bell.
"We are right here."
It rang...
Yeah.
I wonder... if the old guy
and the others heard it.
Yeah, I'm sure of it.
My heart throbs at the thought of you
kimi e no omoi ga takanatte
Limitless power surges
kagirinaki chikara umareru
As long as you wish, we'll
brandish our unchanging bond
motomeru naraba dokomademo
kawaranu kizuna furikazasou
We are hope
The joy of letting our true
feelings fly at each other
kimi to honki de kokoro
butsukeatta yorokobi mo
The pain from how we laughed
our heads off to dry our tears
warai korogete namida
kawakashita setsunasa mo
We connect them together and in the wind Ah
tsunagi awasete kaze no naka Ah
It's fluttering higher and higher
hatameiteiru yo takaku takaku
Why did you give up on your search?
Why sagasu koto wo akirameta no
Why do you keep fighting by yourself?
Why hitori tatakai tsudukeru no
Say, what kind of future did you prepare for?
nee, donna mirai kakugo shita no
Have you fulfilled your dream?
yume wa mou te ni shita no
My heart throbs at the thought of you
kimi e no omoi ga takanatte
Limitless power surges
kagirinaki chikara umareru
If you're bemused, let's wish
quietly to the world for a sunrise
tomadou naraba kono sekai ni
sotto inorou yo ga akeru youni
Close your eyes and listen carefully
me wo tojite mimi wo sumashite
Let's look for your answer
sagashi dasou kimi no kotae wo
As long as you wish, we'll
brandish our unchanging bond
motomeru naraba dokomademo
kawaranu kizuna furikazasou
We are hope
At the broad, blue end of the world
aoku hiroi sekai no hate ni
There is a place I have to return to with you
kimi to mezashitai basho ga aru
The sea route that we take decided long ago
susumiyuku kouro nara tooi mukashi
in the past
mou kimeteita